Finding Aid for the Aaron Enterprises Files PASC.0357
UCLA Library Special Collections
Aarons Enterprises files
1961-1976
UCLA Library Special Collections
Aarons Enterprises
PASC.0357
2.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
During the 1970s, Ruth Aarons was a personal manager of entertainers including George Chakiris, John McMartin, Marcia Wallace, and possibly David Cassidy. The collection consists of a small number of files related to Aarons Enterprises' clients and includes clippings, contracts, correspondence, photographic material, and financial information.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9967062683606533
Biography/History
There is little information available about Ruth Aarons or Aarons Enterprises. Historical information is based on information found in the collection. It appears Ruth Aarons was a personal manager in the entertainment industry who may have formed the company Aarons Enterprises; it is unknown when the company was founded or when it closed for business. During the 1970s Aarons handled the personal management of entertainers such as George Chakiris, John McMartin, and Marcia Wallace. It is believed that David Cassidy was also a client.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of files related to Ruth Aarons and the company Aarons Enterprises. Included are materials related to her clients George Chakiris, John McMartin, and Marica Wallace. Among the files are publicity material such as photographs and clippings; financial documents such as receipts, vouchers and a 1976 ledger; contractual material; and photocopies of correspondence. Additionally there is a small amount of photographic material related to the career of David Cassidy.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Aarons Enterprises (1972, 1975-1976; Boxes 3-5)
George Chakiris (Boxes 1-3; 1958-1973)
John McMartin (Box 1; 1975-1976)
Marcia Wallace (Box 1; 1976)
David Cassidy (Box 1; 1971, 1972)
Theatrical agents -- Archives.; Theatrical agencies -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.
- Aarons Enterprises
  - Aarons Enterprises April 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 Apr (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Aarons Enterprises Aug 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 Aug (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Aarons Enterprises December 1975 Completed Data Processing, 1975 Dec (Box 3, Folder 11)
    General note
    Receipts and disbursements vouchers.
  - Aarons Enterprises February 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 Feb (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Aarons Enterprises January 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 Jan (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Aarons Enterprises July 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 July (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Aarons Enterprises June 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 June (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Aarons Enterprises March 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 Mar (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Aarons Enterprises May 1976 Completed Data Processing, 1976 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Aarons Enterprises November 1975 Completed Data Processing, 1975 Nov (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Aarons Enterprises October 1975 Completed Data Processing, 1975 Oct (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Aarons Enterprises September 1975 Completed Data Processing, 1975 Sep (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Aarons Enterprises, Inc. - ledger, Fiscal Year ending 1976 Aug 31 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Operation Madhouse screenplay treatment by Bill Richmond, no date (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Found near files related to George Chakras.
  - Ruth Aarons desk planner, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- George Chakiris
  - Aarons Management Contract, 1966 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Berlitz - lessons correspondence, 1964 Jan (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Beverly Hills Health Club, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Letter re. Beverly Hills health club statement.
  - Chakiris Passport, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Company - correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Company - correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Company - publicity, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Company - publicity, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Contracts, 1961, 1962, no date (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Copy of terminated personal management contract with Freed and Panavision Incorporated and release agreement.
  - Corn is Green - clippings, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Corn is Green - playbill (2 copies), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Diners Club card, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - El Patio Mexico - publicity, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    With snap shots of billboard ads.
  - Fan Club - correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Furniture purchased in Japan - invoices, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - George Chakiris, 1967, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Bio, photocopies of clippings, and black and white photographs which may be related to a Chakiris production in Las Vegas. Playbill and clipping for Happy Time.
  - George Chakiris, 1969, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Original and photocopied clippings and press releases. Photocopied correspondence to and from Ruth Aarons regarding Chakiris. Of note is information about a contractual dispute regarding Chakiris' involvement in Company.
  - George Chakiris Show - Japan stills, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Appears to be for the George Chakiris Show.
  - George Chakiris Show - Japan tour publicity (tear out), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - George Chakiris souvenir program for Japan show, 1968 Feb-Mar (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Appears to be a souvenir program, in Japanese.
  - Happy Time, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Playbill and newspaper clippings.
  - Happy Time, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Playbills and press.
  - Happy Time - publicity Chequers, Australia, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Index of Miscellaneous File, no date (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Appears to be index for original filing system.
  - Insurance, Automobile, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Irish Co. Contract, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kismet - publicity and reviews, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Lew Wasserman correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mail service redirect in England, 1965 March (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous file of Bekin receipts, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous receipts for post box and clipping service, 1964, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miyako Hotel Billing Matter, 1963, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Personal Date and Interview Questions and Answers, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Publicity-like one sheet with replies to questions asked by fans.
  - Press clippings, 1972 Mar and Sept (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Press clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Publicity - clippings, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Swiss Accounts, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Television - Japan commercial, 1971 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Television - Possible Guest Appearances, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Script for Circle of Fear, clipping regarding Zenith presents A Salute to Television's 25th Anniversary, handwritten notes for Ghost Story, and correspondence regarding Top of the Month show.
  - Tio Taco, M.D., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Employment agreement. Episode of Medical Center.
  - TV commercials - correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Union Trade Associations, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - West Side Story - proof sheets for television rerun, 1972 Feb/March (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - West Side Story - television premiere publicity, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - William Morris loan to Chakiris, 1963 Jan (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - WMA Agency Contracts, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- George Chakiris
  - Baby photographs, 1964 Jan 30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Baby picture and negative of Chakiris and photograph of Athena (sister).
  - Financial miscellaneous memo, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - John McMartin bio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Phyllis - contract, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ruth Aarons Notes, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Hand written jottings, notes, photocopied clippings, and memo type notes. Could be information gathering for a bio.
  - Telegrams - transcriptions, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Television Possible - note to Billy Gold, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Thieves - contract, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - William Morris - contract, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - William Morris correspondence, 1976 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Marcia Wallace
  - Financial miscellaneous memo, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hollywood Squares letter, 1976 Feb 26 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ruth Aaron Notes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Hand written jottings and notes. Could be information gathering for a bio.
  - Telegrams (transcripts), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - William Morris correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- David Cassidy
  - David Cassidy - Ed Careff proof sheets and negatives (folder 1 of 2), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Proof sheets and photographs only.
  - David Cassidy - Ed Careff proof sheets and negatives (folder 2 of 2), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Negatives only.
  - David Cassidy - head shots, 1971 Feb (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Two poses, one with negative.
  - David Cassidy - head shots and negatives, 1971 June (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Multiple copies of what appears to be two poses.
  - David Cassidy - prints and negatives, 1971 June (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Multiple copies of two poses and corresponding negatives.
  - Partridge Family Photos (folder 1 of 2), no date (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Proof sheets and one headshot of David Cassidy. Negative for selected images found in Box 1 folder xx.
  - Partridge Family Photos (folder 2 of 2), no date (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Negatives only. Proof sheet prints for selected images found in Box xx folder xx.